# ROZHKOV DMITRII

#### RUST SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

🛘 +7 929 2477436 | @ rozhkovdmitrii@yandex.ru | 🛅 LinkedIn | 🗘 GitHub | 🕈 Yugorsk, Russia

### **EDUCATION**

# Ulyanovsk State Technical University

Master degree in Computer Science and Facilities

Ulyanovsk, Russia Sep 2003 – Jun 2010

#### **PROFILE**

I am a more than 12 years experienced back-end developer. I have a background mainly in network and fintech services, blockchain. Currently prefer Rust and C++ but also quite good at python - have several projects written on python. I'm fond of Clean Code, SOLID principles and Design Driven Development. Able to establish processes and manage small team. I'm looking for company of hard-working and well rewarding labor culture. I'm self-organized and outgoing person, always able to find a balance between quality and rushing for the quick result for the company sake.

#### SKILLS

Computer languages: Rust, C++, Python, pine-script(Trading View), solidity, java-script, action-script, lua, lisp, assembler

## Tooling:

- Rust: clap, serde, tokio, syn/quote
- Build: cargo, cmake, qmake, GNU make
- **Test and Debug:** sanitizing, mock-all, google test, google mock, boost test framework, cucumber; wireshark(tshark), netcat, [t|wire|shark, tcpreplay, tcpdump, lsof, gdb, strace; TDD/BDD
- Queues: kafka
- DB: postgreSQL, clickhouse, prometheus, mysql, firebird, mongodb, tarantool
- Version control: git, svn, mercurial
- CI/CD: buildkite, GitHub Actions
- Virtualization: vagrant, docker, docker-compose
- Solana: Solana Program Library, Metaplex Program Library, Address Lookup Tables и т.д.
- Ethereum: solidity, truffle, hardhat
- Documentation: Docosaurus, Pelican
- Analytic and logs: Prometheus, Elastic Search (Kebana), Google analytics, Matomo; Vector

Foreign languages: English B2 Upper Intermediate

# EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

# Komodo

X

International, Amsterdam

Mar 2023 – Okt 2023

komodo-defi-framework acting as multichain facilities of komodo Wallet and DEX

- komodefi-cli a command line interface for the komoo defi platfrom, wallet and DEX
- mm2 service an intermediary service provides the komodo defi platform facilities

Rust, clap, serde, hyper, future01

# Neon labs

International, Lisbon  $Sep \ 2021 - Sep \ 2022$ 

L2 Ethterum-compatible middleware based on Solana

- Restructuring design, IPC network layer of *Neon Proxy* (asyncio, tcp, pickle)
- Logging system (python, asyncio, vector, elastic search, kebana)
- Full test suite (Buildkite)
- Analytics gathering. (Prometheus)
- Documentation. (Docosaurus)

International, Singapore

Proprietary proxy services/agents and HFT services

Aug 2020 - Aug 2021

- Infatica http proxy server: ring buffer based http server (c++, nginx sources, libevent, google mock)
- Infatica SDK: library to be plugged into a desktop app to provide a proxy node (C++, Qt, google mock, google analytics, matomo)
- Infatica Android SDK: aar to be plugged into a Android app to provice a proxy node, reasearch and development. (C++, Qt, JNI)
- Infatica trading-desk: a trading platform, design, management, research on strategies, implementing (python, asyncio, plotly dash, pandas, clickhouse, trading view hooks & pinescript, Finam api)

IskraUralTel Russia, Yekaterinburg

Lawful interception systems on telephone and ip networks

Jun 2017 - Aug 2020

• Development facilities for: decoding, transcoding, arranging, encrypting, dumping, life-time management, storing statistics and payload of variety protocols and contents accordingly Russian and European laws (stl, boost, libcurl, libcrypt etc.). Testing them (gooble test and mock). Providing testing telecomunication environment (docker, freeradius server, netcat etc.) Making of interprocess communications, based, generally, on ASN1 and Google Protobuf. Making GUI to manage and debug interception in details (Qt).

### Gazprom Transqas Yuqorsk

Russia, Yugorsk

May 2012 - Aug 2017

Corporate management systems
• Logistic and carrying planning processes automation (1cEnterprise 8.3, javascript).

• Payroll and accounting processes automation (1C Enterprise 7.7)

Simbirsoft Russia, Ulvanovsk

FXCM - project

Nov 2010 - May 2012

- Currency management operations transport layer (C++, xslt, libtpt)
- GUI with Adobe Flex SDK (action script)

Polus-Service LLC.

Russia, Ulyanovsk

Oct 2009 - Nov 2010

- Web sites analytic system. Server-side processing, ranging and saving properly analytic packages(c++, qt-network, qt-service, qt-sql и др). Web site analytic agent (JavaScript)
- Household appliances trading processes maintenance system and online-store «Polus» (php, mysql, jquery, pure.js)

# Ulyanovsk State Technical University

e-commerce services and web analytics systems

Russia, Ulyanovsk

Computer center of computer science faculty

Sep 2007 - Okt 2009

- Adopting High performance computer cluster in educational process (Microsoft HPC Pack SDK, Microsoft HPC Server, mpich 1.2.5, c++, MPI, RSA algorithm)
- Cluster Management Panel Web Site (PHP, Microsoft HPC Server)

#### My Own Projects

#### Python logged groups | GitHub

This package designed to facilitate logging inside classes and functions with @logged\_group decorator and also makes it possible to manage logging level and any different things for any logging domain mentioned in log\_cfg.json